America is having a love affair with "A Little Romance"
A Little Romance is a comedy, romance film directed by George Roy Hill.
Intellectually precocious teenager Lauren King lives in
Paris with her somewhat ditzy mother.
On a movie set, she strikes up a friendship with
teenage film buff Daniel Michon.
After Lauren's mother forbids her to date the outspoken Daniel, the young lovebirds team up with eccentric pickpocket Julius to run
away to Venice, where, according to legend, a couple who kiss under the Bridge of Sighs will stay together forever.
Julius, played by Laurence Olivier.
Lauren King, played by Diane Lane.
Daniel Michon, played by Thelonious Bernard.
Richard King, played by Arthur Hill.
Kay King, played by Sally Kellerman.
Brod, played by Broderick Crawford.
A Little Romance is a 1979 American romantic comedy film directed by George Roy Hill and starring
Laurence Olivier, Thelonious Bernard, and 13-year-old Diane Lane in her film debut.
The screenplay was written by Allan Burns and George Roy Hill, based
on the novel E=mc2 Mon Amour (1977) by Patrick Cauvin.
The original music score was composed by Georges Delerue.
The film follows a French boy and an American girl who meet in Paris and begin a romance that leads to a journey to
Venice where they hope to seal their love forever with a kiss beneath the Bridge of Sighs at sunset.
The film won the 1979 Academy Award for Best Original Score for Georges Delerue and
received an additional nomination for Best Adapted Screenplay for Allan Burns.
It also received two Golden Globe Award nominations for Best Supporting
Actor for Laurence Olivier and Best Original Score for Delerue.
As the film's young leads, Thelonious Bernard and Diane Lane both received Young Artist Award nominations as Best Actor
and Best Actress respectively, as well as earning the film a win as Best Motion Picture Featuring Youth.
It was the first film produced by Orion Pictures.
The film explores themes of paris, france, venice,
italy, bridge, road trip, teen angst.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.